Guide to the Walter Ledyard Todd papers, 1889-1970.
Todd, Walter Ledyard papers, 1889-1970.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Walter Ledyard Todd papers, 1889-1970.
3167
Walter L. Todd, 1886-1971.
9.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence files, business files, scrapbooks, diaries, photographs, and printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence files, business files, scrapbooks, diaries, photographs, and printed material of Walter L. Todd relating to his business, Cornell University and alumni affairs, business dinners and meetings, and personal matters.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Walter L. Todd and his brother George were partners in Todd Associates and owners of Widmer's Wine Cellars in Naples, New York. The family firm, Todd Company, which manufactured office equipment and supplies, had earlier merged with the Burroughs Corporation. Todd was a trustee of and a donor to Cornell University, served as president of the Cornellian Council and as a member of the Cornell University Council, and was active in alumni affairs in Rochester. He became Cornell's 16th Presidential Councillor, a lifetime honor recognizing outstanding alumni, in 1969.
Cornell University Class of 1909.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence files, business files, scrapbooks, diaries, photographs, and printed material of Walter L. Todd relating to his business, Cornell University and alumni affairs, business dinners and meetings, and personal matters.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Todd, Walter L., 1886-1971.; Todd, George.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University.; Cornell University. Class of 1909.; Cornell University. Cornellian Council.; Cornell University. Council.; Todd Associates.; Widmer's Wine Cellars (Naples, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Businessmen.
Form and Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Gannett Foundation, 1955 (Box 1)
- Cornell University Alumni Assoc., 1953-1954 (Box 1)
- Cornell Alumni Fund, 1955 (Box 1)
- Ornithology Laboratory (Dr. Arthur A. Allen), 1956-1959 (Box 1)
- Cornell University (M.P. Catherwood), 1948-1957 (Box 1)
- Cornell University (Foster M. Coffin), 1946-1957 (Box 1)
- Cornell University (Whitney R. Cross), 1943-1946 (Box 1)
- Cornell University (Dr. E.E. Day), 1947-1949 (Box 1)
- Cornell University (Day, Harris & Wilcox), 1944 (Box 1)
- Certificates (Box 1)
- Cornell University (Willard I. Emerson), 1951-1953 (Box 1)
- Cornell University (College of Engineering, Dean S.C. Hollister), 1953-1959 (Box 1)
- Cornell University (Dr. John R. Johnson, Department of Chemistry), 1953-1958 (Box 1)
- Cornell University (Dr. Deane W. Malott), 1953-1959 (Box 1)
- Cornell University (Dean H.B. Meek, School of Hotel Admin.), 1953-1958 (Box 1)
- Cornell University (Dr. William I. Myers, College of Agriculture), 1953-1959 (Box 1)
- W.V. Nixon (Univ. Development, Cornell), 1956-1959 (Box 1)
- J. Robert Williams (Office of Public Info.), 1956-1957 (Box 1)
- Zwingle, Dr. J.L., 1955-1959 (Box 1)
- Cornell Miscellaneous, 1952-1959 (Box 1)
- Cornell Skivington Papers, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
- Cornell Statler Inn, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
- Greater Cornell Committee, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
- Cornell School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1944-1958 (Box 1)
- Cornell Zeta Psi, 1953-1956 (Box 1)
- Cornell University Council, 1955-1959 (Box 1)
- Cornell Fund, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
- Cornell Fund, 1968 (Box 2)
- Cornell Fund - Tower Club, 1968 (Box 2)
- Cornell Miscellaneous, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
- Cornell Miscellaneous, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
- Bausch & Lomb - Dedication, 1966 (Box 2)
- Bausch & Lomb - Carl S. Hallauer, 1959-1963 (Box 2)
- Bausch & Lomb - McManus, 1962-1964 (Box 2)
- Bausch & Lomb - William V. Nixon, 1958-1959 (Box 2)
- Bausch & Lomb - Prof. G.V. Smith, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
- Bausch & Lomb - Dale R. Corson, 1960-1962 (Box 2)
- Bausch & Lomb - Edward Bausch corres. with Provost Peters, 1939-1941 (Box 2)
- Bausch & Lomb - Edward Bausch misc. corres., 1962-1963 (Box 2)
- Bausch & Lomb - Edward Bausch, 1941-1944 (Box 2)
- Pomona College Plan, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
- Admission Procedures (Box 2)
- Centennial, 1964 (Box 2)
- Cornell Aeronautical Laboratory, 1968 (Box 2)
- Cornell University Council Dinner, 1957 (Box 2)
- Cornell University Council Meeting, 1956 (Box 2)
- Cornell Club of New York, 1947-1959 (Box 2)
- Cornell University - School of Business and Public Administration, 1948-1958 (Box 2)
- Cornell University Associates, 1953-1959 (Box 2)
- Cornell Plantations, 1959 (Box 2)
- Cornell University - L.H. Durland, 1954-1960 (Box 2)
- Cornell Club of Rochester, 1947-1959 (Box 2)
- Cornell Alumni Fund, 1956-1959 (Box 3)
- Ithaca, Oct. 21-22 (probably), 1967 (Box 3)
- McMaster Dinner folder, 1970 (Box 3)
- Cornell Class Reunion folder, 1970 (Box 3)
- Dedication of Brookwood Science Information Center (Box 3)
- Rochester Gas & Electric Corporation, 1966 (Box 3)
- Chamber of Commerce, Annual Dinner and other Meetings (Box 3)
- The Federation of Churches, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
- Monroe County Library System (2 folders), 1956-1957 (Box 3)
- Rochester Chamber of Commerce, 1960 (Box 3)
- Rehabilitation Commission Advisory Comm., 1955-1958 (Box 3)
- Navy League of the United States (2), 1949-1952 (Box 3)
- Non-Property Taxes Comm. Meetings, 1949-1951 (Box 3)
- Rochesterians & Rochester Convention and Publicity Bureau, 1949 (Box 3)
- Rochester Civic Development Co. (2), 1948-1949 (Box 3)
- "Odds and Ends" (mainly printed matter) (Box 3)
- Letters written by Walter Todd to his mother while he was at Cornell, 1907-1909 (Box 4)
- Printed pamphlets (Box 5)
- Salesman's order book of G.W. Todd & Co. manufacturers of the protectograph, 1910-1911 (Box 6)
- Chronological Record of G.W. Todd & Company and successor companies, 1899-1958 (Box 6)
- Reports: Walter L. Todd - Term papers for various courses at Cornell, 1909 (Box 6)
- Diaries of Walter L. Todd, 1933-1970 (Box 6)
- Cash book, 1907-1909 (Box 7)
- Ledger, ca. 1912 (Box 7)
- Cornell Scrapbook, 1923-1927 (Box 7)
- Scrapbook - Tribute drive in honor of Walter L. Todd, July 5-23, 1927 (Box 7)
- Scrapbook of postcards - Scenes in foreign countries, n.d. (Box 7)
- Scrapbook (Mostly Cornell Material), 1905-1927 (Box 8)
- Scrapbook (Mostly Cornell Material), 1923-1926 (Box 8)
- Scrapbook of Letters - re: "Cornell Book of Views", 1925 (Box 8)
- Scrapbook (Mostly Cornell Material), 1904-1925 (Box 8)
- Scrapbook of European Trip, 1927 (Box 9)
- Scrapbook (Mostly Cornell Material), 1902-1922 (Box 9)
- Correspondence re: Cornell Book of Views (Box 10)
- Newspaper clippings concerning the Todd Family and others (Box 10)
- Printed material re: Rochester, N.Y. and others (Box 10)
- Cornelliana (Box 10)
- Misc. letters and photos (Box 10)
- 1 bound vol. "Sales recpt. 1915 Letters." (Box 10)
- 1 bound vol. Sales recpt., 1916 (Box 10)
- 1 framed picture of crew poster, Cornell not specifically identified, crew men have "C" on shirts. Item loaned to Cornell in Washington office for 10 yrs. until 4-11-1995. (Box 10)
- Cornell Scrapbook, 1905-1909 (Box 11)